Having a rival can keep you committed to achieving your goals and enhance your overall performance.
有一个竞争对手，能让你始终致力于实现自己的目标，并提升你的整体表现。
But before you go out and find an entrepreneur to outcompete, it’s important to understand and avoid the traps that often come with rivalry.
但在你出去物色一位创业者、想要在竞争中胜过对方之前，重要的是先了解并避开与对手较量时常常随之而来的陷阱。
After all, competitive rivalry can also hinder effective decision-making and increase your willingness to take risks, behaviors that can ultimately hurt your venture’s success.
毕竟，与对手较量也可能妨碍你做出有效的决策，并让你更愿意冒险，而这些行为最终可能有损你企业的成功。
Finding someone you’re committed to outcompeting can be a great way to stay focused on your goals and push your venture to the next level.
找到一个你决心在竞争中胜过的人，会是一个很好的办法，能让你始终专注于目标，把企业推向新的高度。
But when you’re intently focused on outperforming your rivals, you may begin to develop a “win-at-all-costs” mentality that causes you to ignore how you achieve success.
但是，一旦你一心专注于胜过对手，就可能开始形成一种“不惜一切代价求胜”的心态，导致你忽视自己用什么方式取得成功。
One group of researchers, for example, examined the link between rivalry and unethical behavior.
例如，有一组研究人员考察了对手间的较量与不道德行为之间的关联。
They found that when people compete against their rivals, they are more willing to behave unethically to win.
他们发现，人们与对手竞争时，更愿意为了取胜而做出不道德的行为。
But such behavior may stain your reputation and strain relationships important to your success.
但这类行为可能会玷污你的声誉，并使那些对你的成功很重要的关系变得紧张。
One way to avoid this trap is to stop and reflect on what’s important.
避开这一陷阱的一个方法是停下来，反思什么才是重要的。
While outperforming your rivals may provide short-term benefits, the loss of your integrity will have long-term consequences.
虽然胜过对手或许能带来短期利益，但失去诚信将会造成长期后果。
One reason having a rival can enhance your venture’s performance is that it creates a level of excitement that drives you to work harder.
有竞争对手能提升你企业的业绩，原因之一在于它会带来一定程度的兴奋感，驱使你更加努力地工作。
But this eagerness to win may also hurt your venture’s success, particularly when it causes you to make impulsive, irrational decisions.
但这种急于求胜的心情也可能有损你企业的成功，尤其是在它导致你做出冲动、不理性的决定时。
But it’s possible to avoid such costly mistakes by making a habit of engaging in critical thinking, such as considering opposing viewpoints and conducting cost-benefit analyses, especially for those decisions that are complex and can determine the future of your venture.
但这类代价高昂的错误是可以避免的，办法是养成批判性思考的习惯，比如考虑对立的观点、开展成本效益分析，尤其是在面对那些复杂且能决定你企业未来的决策时。
The sense of eagerness that comes with having a rival can not only cause you to make poorer decisions but also lead you to take greater risks that put your venture in peril.
有了竞争对手，随之而来的急切感不仅可能让你做出更糟糕的决定，还可能促使你冒更大的风险，使你的企业陷入危险。
One way you can overcome the risk-inducing effects of rivalry that stand to endanger your venture’s success is to remain attentive to your emotional state and actively monitor how such feelings are affecting your decision-making.
与对手较量会诱发冒险倾向，这种影响很可能危及你企业的成功；要克服它，一个办法是始终留意自己的情绪状态，并主动监测这些情绪正如何影响你的决策。